Dana Paige Seidel

National Science Foundation Data Science Fellow & UC Berkeley PhD Candidate with 10 years experience in data wrangling and statistical modeling in R specifically for spatial and time series data. Ongoing contributor to popular ggplot2 (R) package, co-author of scales package.

CONTACT

- dana.seidel@gmail.com
- https://www.danaseidel.com
- **6**12.232.6708 **9** @dpseidel
- Opseidel Apseidel dana-seidel

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

PhD in Environmental Science, Policy, & Management Expected May 2019 | Berkeley, CA

UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA

MSc IN BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES Aug 2014 | Edmonton, AB, Canada Concentration in Ecology

CORNELL UNIVERSITY

BSc in Natural Resources

May 2011 | Ithaca, NY

Concentration in applied ecology College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Graduated *cum laude*

SKILLS

- R Data Analysis Tidyverse
- Geospatial Analysis (R, Python, ArcGIS)
- Version Control, Git/Github
- Data Visualization Biostatistics
- Regression Analysis Open Science
- Experimental Design Teaching
- R Markdown LaTeX Shiny
- Open Source Development in R
- Web Development SQL

AWARDS

- Data Science for the 21st Century: National Science Foundation Research Traineeship (\$32K, 2015-2017)
- Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor Award, UC Berkeley 2018
- Letter of Commendation for Excellence in Teaching, Univ. of Alberta 2012

PUBLICATIONS

For full list of my publications, please see Google Scholar **☞**

EXPERIENCE

$\textbf{RSTUDIO} \mid \texttt{Software Development Intern} \cdot \texttt{Tidyverse Team}$

June 2018 - Aug 2018 | Remote

- Participated in open source R development for ggplot2 (486K downloads/month) and scales packages
- Learned the internals of a large existing codebase to resolve issues, submit bug fixes, add new features, write tests, and update documentation to provide better functionality for user-defined scales, themes, and aesthetics manipulation during data visualization in R.

GOOGLE | QUANTITATIVE ANALYST INTERN • GEODATA ANALYTICS TEAM May 2016 - Aug 2016 | Mountain View, CA

- Explored impressions data for millions of features in the Google Maps database using Dremel, R
- Assessed average time to impressions maturity for novel business features using hazard models.
- Fit mixed effect regression models and evaluated model capacity for predicting impressions of novel business features based upon spatial relations with mature features.

RESEARCH

GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER | UC BERKELEY

- Developed an R package to streamline best practices in exploratory data analysis for movement data and automate building polished reports
- Developed an R shiny application for updating spatial risk maps of infectious disease using rare events logistic regression & spatial libraries in Python and R. ♥ ♠
- Built spatiotemporal models estimating disease prevalence and spread using a hierarchical Bayesian framework in WinBUGs and R.

SOUTHWEST ALBERTA MONTANE RESEARCH PROJECT (

- Designed database and analysis flow for foraging & movement data from 182 radio-collared elk totaling 856K cleaned GPS samples.
- Implemented multivariate regression analyses in R, including mixed negative binomial regression and paired conditional logistic regression

TFACHING

VISITING INSTRUCTOR | HONG KONG UNIVERSITY

January 2018 | Movement Ecology in R Workshop

Co-developed and led an 8-day workshop teaching ecological methods of spatial and movement analysis in R & RStudio. 🛇 🔾

DATA SCIENCE INSTRUCTOR | UC BERKELEY

Fall 2017 ESPM 157 • Spring 2018 ESPM 288

Taught upper division course teaching collaborative & reproducible data science including programming in R & RStudio, relational databases, data management, version control, remote data and APIs, cloud computing, & R Markdown.

BIOSTATISTICS INSTRUCTOR | UC BERKELEY Fall 2015 ESPM 173

Taught upper division biostatistics course including basic hypothesis testing, probability, experimental design, linear models, and programming in R & RStudio.